David K. Storrs

dstorrs.public+job@gmail.com (415) 913-7576

SUMMARY

15+ years software development experience

Architect and code author, team lead, and manager with both strategic and tactical experience

Extensive knowledge of Perl, Node, Javascript, MongoDB and various RDBMSs

Github: http://github.com/dstorrs [cf Copper in particular]

SKILLS

Programming: Perl; Javascript; Objective-C, C/C++, PHP, Ruby, various others

Operating Systems: UNIX, Mac OS X

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Oracle

Web: HTML, CSS, Javascript, ¡Query, Catalyst, Node.js, Ruby / Rails

Management: Experience at all levels of the organization: CEO / CTO, architect, team lead, team member. Specific

skills include: strategic planning, time and cost estimation, scheduling, technical to non-technical communication, documentation, and mentoring of on- and off-site subordinates.

Preference for Agile methodologies.

EXPERIENCE

5/2010-2/2013 ChannelMeter Inc

San Francisco, CA

Co-Founder and CTO. Analytics for YouTube publishers.

Perl, Catalyst, SQL, git. Later migrated to Go + Ruby/Rails, and MongoDB to ease hiring.

5/2008-4/2010 IonZero LLC

NY, NY

Senior Developer. Worked on various client projects.

Perl, Catalyst, SQL on various RDBMSs, Git and Subversion.

01/2008-5/2008 Pica9, Inc

NY, NY

Director of Programming, Managed and trained development team and wrote code on business-critical applications. Perl and PHP, Catalyst, Subversion, MySQL

11/2005-9/2007 Wotan LLC

Southport, Connecticut

CEO and Founder. Web-based network graph diagramming.

Secured \$800,000 in angel funding, managed a team, released two products (Kayuda and KayudaMaps).

10/2003-11/2005 OnyxNeon

Shelton, Connecticut

CT Regional Affiliate. Wrote code, did business development, managed subcontractors, wrote specifications. Perl, C++, Catalyst, SQL, XML, Subversion, various RDBMSs; platform varied by project

10/2002-10/2003 Flexi International

Shelton, Connecticut

Manager of Custom Projects; Liased with customers, programmed, wrote specs & documentation, and managed the development team on those issues.

C++, XML, Rational ClearCase/Quantify/Purify/Rose, Development on Windows 98

8/2002-10/2002 Yale University

New Haven, Connecticut

Contract work; reverse engineered their proprietary database and migrated it to Oracle. Helped select the vendor to provide the new data maangement system. Managed a subcontractor.

Perl, XML, Agile Development on Unix, contact with and technical evaluation of vendors

3/2001-6/2002 AdOne/PowerOne Media Inc

New York, New York

Senior Developer / Team Lead on a project to update the company's technology to enterprise quality. Analyzed existing systems for failure points; designed and built solutions. Rearchitected workflows for migration from flat file database to Oracle. Introduced Pair Programming, Test First Design, Unit Testing, Refactoring, and Iteration Planning. Managed a team of four programmers.

Oracle, C++, Perl, XML, STL, CVS, Agile Development on Unix

1/2000-12/2000 Miacomet /Katerra Corp

Springfield, Massachussetes

Developer on the zVerse project, Team Lead on Real Feel Fishin' game. C++, Perl, STL, CVS on Win2K/Win98.

7/1999-12/1999 Maine School of Science and Mathematics

Limestone, Maine

Taught physics and computer science to gifted high school students

Worked at two separate summer programs, teaching HTML and virtual reality coding.

11/1998-6/1999 **Playlink (UGO/ActionWorld)**

New York, New York

Developer on a team producing a Java-based Web gamesite. Designed, documented, implemented, and maintained games and game components.

Java, Perl, CVS on Win98

7/1998-11/1998 **Register.com**

New York, New York

Developer and co-designer on the mission-critical backend infrastructure. Also maintained legacy code and managed contractors.

Perl, database design, MySQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CVS

2/1998-7/1998 **D.I.D.Inc**,

New York, New York

Developer on the Electronic Documentation System (Paine Webber), and the Java Desktop (inhouse) Perl, Java, CVS on Win95

11/1997-2/1998 **CCG Metamedia**

New York, New York

Game Developer for a virtual-reality system. C++

8/1995-11/1997 Crossover Technologies

New York, New York

Developer on a CD-based RTS game (Evolution), and two Web games Reinventing America I and II, and President '96 RDBMS design, FoxPro 3.2, C++, MS Sourcesafe, MFC on Win95

6/1994-6/1995 Evaluation Associates, Inc

Norwalk, Connecticut

Financial analyst in the Performance Measurement department. Tracked, verified, and reported on the performance of various money managers

EDUCATION

9/1990-6/1994 **Oberlin College**

Oberlin, Ohio

Studied English and Computer Science, graduated in May 1994 (Bachelor's degree).

References available upon request